

Introduction

After half a decade in teaching, I made the decision to challenge myself and start a career in a long held interest of mine: development. For eighteen months I taught myself how to develop websites, starting with the basics of HTML all the way to full stack sites using React with NodeJS. In January I started my first role as a Junior Web Developer / Onsite Technician and am now flourishing in the tech sector.

Of course, I still have the skills and knowledge I gained as a teacher and put them to use everyday - whether it's helping colleagues with projects, using my interpersonal skills with the public when onsite, or effectively managing my time while juggling several builds at the same time. I also still tutor students taking their GCSE Maths exams.

Outside of work I am an avid gamer and spend much of my time reading and sometimes writing fiction. Recently I joined a local archery club and am looking forward to starting competitions next year.

Employment History

Junior Web Developer / Onsite Technician, LiveBuzz, Coventry

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

In this role I work in a tight knit team of around 11 developers to design, create and deploy registration pages for corporate events hosting up to 100,000 visitors. I work productively alongside relationship managers and clients to create bespoke products that fulfil a wide variety of needs.

While some projects require a team effort, I also work independently to create sites using Laravel, PHP, JavaScript, HTML and SCSS, and as a team we use Git to streamline complex builds.

A second part of this role requires me to work onsite to build and maintain registration areas for customers to use while attending events. In this side of the role I manage a team of staff to assist visiting customers, maintain a positive relationship with clients, and ensure a smooth registration process.

Maths Tutor

JANUARY 2023 - PRESENT

Alongside my work as a developer I tutor students taking their GCSE Mathematics exams. I have successfully taken students from being anxious about their exams to confident pupils who are proud of the results they achieve by being a reliable, hardworking tutor who forges positive relationships with both the students and their parents.

Supply Teacher, Aspire Education, Warwickshire

SEPTEMBER 2022 - JANUARY 2023

While searching for my first role as a developer I worked for several months as a Supply teacher at a dozen schools in the Warwickshire area. I worked tirelessly with challenging students to step in when teachers were unable to be in the lesson.

Details

Nuneaton, Warwickshire
United Kingdom
07792579865
olliecrawford42@gmail.com

Links

Portfolio

GitHub

LinkedIn

Primary Skills

JavaScript

PHP

NodeJS

React

Python

Although the role was unpredictable and often required a great deal of effort from myself to maintain decorum in unstable classrooms, the leadership skills and ability to improvise will stay with me for a long time.

Teacher of Mathematics & Computer Science, Ashlawn School, Rugby

JANUARY 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2022

This role entailed all you would expect from a modern secondary school teacher - maintaining behaviour standards, working with students and parents to foster relationships and improve results, and administrative duties to keep everything in check. On top of the time management and interpersonal skills needed in a teaching role, I also needed the dedication and discipline to work outside of school hours and always needed to be organised. I also helped create and run a chess club and maths tutoring as extra-curricular activities.

Teacher of Mathematics, Harris C of E Academy

SEPTEMBER 2018 - DECEMBER 2019

Harris was the first school I taught at as a qualified teacher. I taught children from Year 7 to Year 11 Mathematics while managing to complete the various tasks, observations and activities needed to pass my NQT year. This was no small effort but I accomplished it well through use of hard work, my nurturing nature, and working as a team with other teachers at Harris.

Education / Courses

Software Development Bootcamp, Hyperion Dev

DECEMBER 2022 - MARCH 2023

To expand my repertoire as a developer I applied to complete this University of Manchester co-certified Software Development Bootcamp. During the bootcamp, I developed a strong understanding of core Python concepts such as data types, variables, conditionals, loops, functions, and object-oriented programming. I honed my skills in writing clean, efficient, and well-documented code, fostering best practices in software development.

Full Stack Web Development, Self-taught

Over the course of around nine months I used various online courses to teach myself full stack web development. Before starting I had no experience working with code, and now I am able to use HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React and Node to create full stack web applications. I also learnt used MongoDB for NoSQL databases. Learning all of this while balancing a full time job as a teacher was challenging, but through determination, hard work and willpower I achieved success in my endeavours and managed to secure a first web developer position.

PGCE Secondary Maths, Bishop Grosseteste University

SEPTEMBER 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2018

Passed with Distinction

Drama (BA Hons), University of Lincoln, Lincoln

SEPTEMBER 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2015

Graduated with a 2:1